# James Pickard B.Sc. (Hons)

# iames.pickard@gmail.com +44 7821 280 175

Six years in lead roles for eCommerce, point-of-sale, lottery, API, mobile games. Developing web applications since 2002 with a passion for creating software that makes life easier. First-Class Honours degree in Computer Science with AI from the University of London.

#### **Experience**

June 2016 - Present. Bungay, England.

Green Dragon

- Proprietor of a public house and brewery.
- Responsibility for all aspects of running the pub and brewery: HR, payroll, rotas, VAT, stock control, pricing, maintenance, training, quality assurance.
  - Documented end-to-end brewing process in "Brew Bible" for fast onboarding of new hires.
  - Designed and built a web-accessible temperature monitoring system using Raspberry Pis.
- Developed software for accounting, stock control, inventory, scheduling, task management (PHP, Laravel, Vue.JS, MySQL).

Apri 2014 – May 2016. Montreal, Canada.

- Lightspeed
- Technical Lead for a middleware connecting a legacy point-of-sale solution with a new eCommerce system (PHP, Laravel, MySQL, Redis, Node.JS). Responsibility for managing stakeholder expectation across multiple teams and timezones.
  - Built a tool for Support to view the state of the middleware (Node.js, Redis, React).
  - Technical Lead for an eCommerce solution written in PHP (PHP, MySQL, Yii, HTML, JavaScript).
- Day-to-day tasks include code review, technical analysis, prioritisation, coaching other developers, technical writing and documentation, code refactoring and profiling, testing.

From June 2013 - January 2014. Sabbatical while Canadian permanent residence application is processed.

February 2008 – June 2013. London, England; Moncton, Canada; Montreal, Canada. OpenBet Technologies Ltd.

- Software Engineer for Loto-Québec and British Columbia Lottery Corporation teams. Working with industry leading partners IGT to deliver online gaming systems.
- Technical Lead for Mobile Games. Porting Flash-based games to iOS using web technologies.
- Technical Lead to delivery of multi-million-dollar provincial betting platform for Atlantic Lottery Corporation. Leading a team of 10 people, first point of customer contact, day-to-day managerial and technical roles including line management, code review, requirements analysis, software design specification, system configuration. Sole responsibility for data migration from legacy system.
- Senior Developer on API team providing an XML interface for bet placement, payments, customer management, liability calculation, event hierarchy.
- Customer-facing experience with industry-leading UK-based bookmakers including Ladbrokes, William Hill, Paddy Power.
- Ongoing support, including remote administration involving troubleshooting time-critical live issues.

July 2006 – July 2008. Bungay, England.

Self employed web development, network troubleshooting and consulting.

November 2002 – June 2003. Bungay, England.

Partner, Open Computer Solutions.

Founder of computer troubleshooting and sales business.

## Qualifications

September 2003 - June 2006

Royal Holloway, University of London

B.Sc. Computer Science with Artificial Intelligence, First-class Honours.

## **Skills**

#### General

- Experience architecting scalable, reliable, modular high transaction-volume systems.
- Experience with every stage of the software lifecycle from requirements gathering to deployment, to ongoing maintenance.
- Experience leading development teams of 10 people or more whilst managing expectations from outside stakeholders including design, legal, business, finance, management.
- Experience running a business.
- Intermediate level French speaking.

## Languages & Technologies

- PHP, JavaScript, Laravel, Typescript, React, Redux, Vue.JS, MySQL, NodeJS, Redis, React, Tcl, Python, Ruby, vim, linux command line, git, subversion, CVS, Jira.

## Online profiles

Github <a href="https://github.com/euoia">https://github.com/euoia</a>

Linked In <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/james-pickard-24394040/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/james-pickard-24394040/</a>

## Notable Open Source Projects

www.learnfrenchverbs.com A website to practise French verb conjugation.

https://github.com/euoia/node-reverb

<u>Bixitime.com</u> A website that shows nearby bikes for Montreal's bike-share scheme.

https://github.com/euoia/bixitime-website

https://github.com/euoia/bixitime-api

https://github.com/euoia/bixitime-poller

Node-Mud: A multi-user text-based environment written to explore Typescript.

https://github.com/euoia/node-mud

Hexbusters: An implementation of the classic board game Hex with an Monte-Carlo Tree Search AI using web workers (JavaScript, React, Redux):

https://github.com/euoia/hexbusters

#### **Additional Information**

British citizen with Canadian permanent residence valid until 2022. Clean British & Quebec driving licenses. Fluent English, intermediate level French.

## References are available on request.